#你看這紅像草
Have a look at the red elephant grass!
#這紅象草 有一點老了哦 可以給竹鼠吃了
This red elephant grass, is a bit old now and can be given to the bamboo rats.
#砍一點給竹鼠吃
Let me chop some for the bamboo rats.
#我去下面來看
Let me have a look down there.
#現在快冬天了
It will be winter very soon.
#如果不砍掉等下它會死掉 也會死掉的
They would simply die, they would die even if I leave them here.
#這種水份比較足的 這種 水份很足的
This type is more juicy. This type, is very juicy,
#比那個還足 (註︰比哪個？)
more juicy than those.
#把這個先砍成一段一段
I chop them into chunks first.
#這個要省著點吃
I can't be too generous.
#不能給它吃太多
I couldn't afford keeping them,
#不然我養不起它的
if I give them too much at a time.
#先給竹鼠吃一下 (註︰這句沒有很好的直譯，所以改了字眼，意思不變就算了)
That's already enough for them.
#因為等一下就要晚 (註︰不知他是說錯還是想說晚餐，還是其他的)
Cuz they'll have din...
#等一下我們就要餵米糠拌飯了
I'll give them rice with bran afterwards.
#先給它們
So I will,
#吃一點點 不要吃那麼多
just give them a bit, not too much.
#吃多了等一下晚上
Otherwise they wouldn't have any appetite,
#它不喜歡吃米糠拌飯
for the rice and bran in the evening.
#給你們加餐
Your extra meal!
#很好吃的哦
C'mon! It's tasty!
#你看 它們開始吃啦
Look! They start eating.
#吃啊
Just eat!
#好吃的
It's tasty!
#這個給你們吃
It's for you.
#好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
#這個我要等一下餵它 等一下餵
I'll give them the rest, give them the rest,
#等 等一下我餵完米糠拌飯再給它們吃
af...after feeding them with the rice and bran.